[
{
    "question": "51. When you are uncoupling a loaded trailer, lower the landing gear until it:",
    "choices": [
        "a. Reaches the ground.",
        "b. Makes contact with the ground and leaves the trailer off the fifth wheel.",
        "c. Makes firm contact with the ground."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Makes firm contact with the ground."
},
{
    "question": "52. When coupling, the proper position of the fifth wheel is:",
    "choices": [
        "a. Level with the ground.",
        "b. Tilted down toward the end of the tractor.",
        "c. Tilted up toward the end of the tractor."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Tilted down toward the end of the tractor."
},
{
    "question": "53. Air and electrical lines from the tractor to the trailer should be:",
    "choices": [
        "a. Resting on the frame of the tractor.",
        "b. Pulled tight with very little slack.",
        "c. Secured, but with enough slack for turns."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Secured, but with enough slack for turns."
},
{
    "question": "54. When backing a tractor under a trailer you should:",
    "choices": [
        "a. Do it quickly to ensure that the kingpin is locked into the fifth wheel.",
        "b. Always use the lowest reverse gear.",
        "c. Always approach the trailer at a slight angle."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Always use the lowest reverse gear."
},
{
    "question": "55. Compared to a straight truck or bus there are _________ things to inspect in combination vehicles.",
    "choices": [
        "a. Fewer.",
        "b. The same number.",
        "c. More."
    ],
    "answer": "c. More."
},
{
    "question": "56. You have coupled with a semitrailer. Where should you put the trailer supports before driving away?",
    "choices": [
        "a. 3 turns off the top with the crank handle secured in its bracket.",
        "b. Raised 1/2 way with the crank handle secured in its bracket.",
        "c. Fully raised with the crank handle secured in its bracket."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Fully raised with the crank handle secured in its bracket."
},
{
    "question": "57. While checking if the trailer is securely coupled to the tractor, the landing gears should:",
    "choices": [
        "a. Fully lowered.",
        "b. Fully raised.",
        "c. Slightly raised."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Slightly raised."
},
{
    "question": "58. After you lock the kingpin into the fifth wheel, you should check the connection by pulling:",
    "choices": [
        "a. Forward 50 feet, turning right, and left.",
        "b. The tractor ahead gently with the trailer brakes locked.",
        "c. The tractor ahead sharply to release the trailer brakes."
    ],
    "answer": "b. The tractor ahead gently with the trailer brakes locked."
},
{
    "question": "59. After the trailer has been coupled to the tractor, the tractor protection control valve should be placed in what position?",
    "choices": [
        "a. Down.",
        "b. Up.",
        "c. Normal."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Normal."
},
{
    "question": "60. The tractor protection valve will close and the trailer emergency brakes will come on when there is a major leak in the________ brake line.",
    "choices": [
        "a. Emergency.",
        "b. Parking.",
        "c. Service."
    ],
    "answer": "a. Emergency."
},
{
    "question": "61. To unlock the fifth wheel, pull the release handle to the ________________ position.",
    "choices": [
        "a. Neutral.",
        "b. Open.",
        "c. Closed."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Open."
},
{
    "question": "62. Off-tracking or cheating causes which of these to follow the wider path while making a turn?",
    "choices": [
        "a. 53-feet bobtail.",
        "b. Triple towing a 45-feet trailer.",
        "c. Tractor with two 27-feet trailers."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Triple towing a 45-feet trailer."
},
{
    "question": "63. To stop a trailer skid you should:",
    "choices": [
        "a. Use the trailer hand brakes.",
        "b. Countersteer.",
        "c. Release the brakes."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Release the brakes."
},
{
    "question": "64. When should you use the hand valve to park a combination vehicle?",
    "choices": [
        "a. To park at loading docks.",
        "b. To park on a grade.",
        "c. Never."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Never."
},
{
    "question": "65. When checking the trailer emergency brakes, on the tractor protection control valve should be placed in the __________ position?",
    "choices": [
        "a. Emergency.",
        "b. Normal.",
        "c. Neutral."
    ],
    "answer": "a. Emergency."
},
{
    "question": "66. What gear should the tractor engine be in after you uncouple from the trailer and are inspecting the trailer supports?",
    "choices": [
        "a. Neutral.",
        "b. Low Reverse.",
        "c. High Reverse."
    ],
    "answer": "a. Neutral."
},
{
    "question": "67. You are uncoupling a trailer. After you shut off the trailer air supply and lock the trailer brakes, you should:",
    "choices": [
        "a. Begin to lower the trailer landing gear.",
        "b. Immediately put on your tractor parking brakes.",
        "c. Back up gently to ease pressure on the fifth wheel locking jaws."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Back up gently to ease pressure on the fifth wheel locking jaws."
},
{
    "question": "68. Combination vehicles are usually heavier, longer, and require more driving skill than single commercial vehicles.",
    "choices": [
        "a. True.",
        "b. False."
    ],
    "answer": "a. True."
},
{
    "question": "69. More than half of truck driver deaths in crashes are the result of rollovers. Trucks turn over easier when fully loaded and are:",
    "choices": [
        "a. Two times more likely to rollover in a crash than empty rigs.",
        "b. Five times more likely to rollover in a crash than empty rigs.",
        "c. Ten times more likely to rollover in a crash than empty rigs."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Ten times more likely to rollover in a crash than empty rigs."
},
{
    "question": "70. When you turn suddenly while pulling doubles, which trailer is most likely to turn over?",
    "choices": [
        "a. The rear trailer is twice as likely to turn over as the tractor.",
        "b. The front trailer is twice as likely to turn over as the tractor.",
        "c. Each trailer is equally likely to turn over as the tractor."
    ],
    "answer": "a. The rear trailer is twice as likely to turn over as the tractor."
},
{
    "question": "71. Why should you not use the trailer hand brake to straighten out a jackknifing trailer?",
    "choices": [
        "a. Because the brake handle is too hard to reach.",
        "b. Because the brakes on the trailer wheels cause the skid in the first place.",
        "c. Because the brakes on the trailer wheels will not respond to the hand brake."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Because the brakes on the trailer wheels cause the skid in the first place."
},
{
    "question": "72. What is a tractor jackknife?",
    "choices": [
        "a. When you lock up the drive tires on the trailer and the trailer spins out sideways as the tractor continues to push forward.",
        "b. When you lock up the drive tires on the tractor and the tractor spins out sideways as the trailer continues to push forward.",
        "c. Neither of these answers are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "b. When you lock up the drive tires on the tractor and the tractor spins out sideways as the trailer continues to push forward."
},
{
    "question": "73. You should swing wide to the left before starting a 90-degree turn to the right?",
    "choices": [
        "a. Yes.",
        "b. No."
    ],
    "answer": "b. No."
},
{
    "question": "74. Why should you not use the trailer hand valve while driving?",
    "choices": [
        "a. Because it won't work as well as the foot brake.",
        "b. Because you should use the parking brake.",
        "c. Because of the danger of making the trailer skid."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Because of the danger of making the trailer skid."
},
{
    "question": "75. Describe what the trailer air supply control does:",
    "choices": [
        "a. It is used to supply the trailer with air, shut the air off, and put on the trailer emergency brakes.",
        "b. It is a yellow, six-sided knob used to control the tractor protection valve.",
        "c. It is a device used to keep the trailer behind the tractor."
    ],
    "answer": "a. It is used to supply the trailer with air, shut the air off, and put on the trailer emergency brakes."
}
]
